[{"Title": "Edwin Poots to \u2018expedite\u2019 Irish language legislation for North", "URL": "https://www.irishtimes.com/news/politics/edwin-poots-to-expedite-irish-language-legislation-for-north-1.4584329", "Cards": [{"Question": "Edwin Poots to \u2018expedite\u2019 \\{\\{0:Irish language legislation\\}\\} for \\{\\{1:North\\}\\}\nSinn F\u00e9in\u2019s O\u2019Neill demands action on issue ahead of re-nomination of first minister\n\\{\\{2:DUP leader Edwin Poots\\}\\} has pledged to implement Irish language legislation at Stormont as quickly as possible.", "Answer": "Irish language legislation, North, DUP leader Edwin Poots"}, {"Question": "\\{\\{0:Mr Poots\\}\\} said \\{\\{1:Stormont leaders\\}\\} have also agreed to convene a summit to tackle spiralling healthcare waiting lists in the \\{\\{2:North\\}\\}.", "Answer": "Mr Poots, Stormont leaders, North"}, {"Question": "\\{\\{0:DUP leader Edwin Poots\\}\\} has pledged to implement \\{\\{1:Irish language legislation\\}\\} at \\{\\{2:Stormont\\}\\} as quickly as possible.", "Answer": "DUP leader Edwin Poots, Irish language legislation, Stormont"}, {"Question": "\u201cI\u2019ve indicated that I will ask my first minister, whoever that happens to be, to expedite all aspects of \\{\\{0:New Decade\\}\\}, \\{\\{1:New Approach\\}\\} in a timely fashion and as quickly as possible, and that is my commitment to the people of Northern Ireland.\u201d", "Answer": "New Decade, New Approach, North"}, {"Question": "\u201cI am committed to fulfilling all aspects of \\{\\{0:New Decade\\}\\}, \\{\\{1:New Approach\\}\\},\u201d he told \\{\\{2:BBC Radio Ulster\\}\\}.", "Answer": "New Decade, New Approach, BBC Radio Ulster"}, {"Question": "When \\{\\{0:ousted DUP leader Arlene Foster\\}\\} resigns as \\{\\{1:First Minister\\}\\}, \\{\\{2:Ms O\u2019Neill\\}\\} is automatically removed from her post as well \u2013 as the joint office can only function if both positions are filled.", "Answer": "ousted DUP leader Arlene Foster, First Minister, Ms O\u2019Neill"}, {"Question": "\\{\\{0:Ms O\u2019Neill\\}\\} said \\{\\{1:Sinn F\u00e9in\\}\\} had told \\{\\{2:Mr Poots\\}\\} in \u201cno uncertain terms around what\u2019s required in order to be back around the table and us all to be able to do business together\u201d.", "Answer": "Ms O\u2019Neill, Sinn F\u00e9in, Mr Poots"}]}, {"Title": "G7 ministers to discuss far-reaching deal on corporate tax", "URL": "https://www.irishtimes.com/business/economy/g7-ministers-to-discuss-far-reaching-deal-on-corporate-tax-1.4583263", "Cards": [{"Question": "The US is leading calls for an agreement at the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) on a major overhaul of \\{\\{0:corporate tax rules\\}\\}, a process which threatens \\{\\{1:Irish tax revenue\\}\\} and also the use of a low tax regime to attract \\{\\{2:multinationals\\}\\}.", "Answer": "corporate tax rules, Irish tax revenue, multinationals"}, {"Question": "The Minister for Finance Paschal Donohoe, will attend the meeting, which starts on Friday, in his role as president of the Eurogroup of finance ministers and will discuss \\{\\{0:corporate tax\\}\\} at a \\{\\{1:bilateral meeting\\}\\} on Saturday with \\{\\{2:US treasury secretary\\}\\}, Janet Yellen.", "Answer": "corporate tax, bilateral meeting, US treasury secretary"}, {"Question": "\nUK focus\nMr Sunak, has underlined the UK\u2019s focus on the part of \\{\\{0:the global \\{\\{1:tax\\}\\} reform agenda\\}\\} relating to \\{\\{2:big multinationals\\}\\} paying tax in markets where they sell via the imposition of a digital sales tax.", "Answer": "the global tax reform agenda, tax, big multinationals"}, {"Question": "This would reduce the amount of tax which some big players pay in Ireland with the Department of \\{\\{1:Finance\\}\\} pencilling in a possible revenue loss of up to \u20ac2 billion per annum, out of \\{\\{2:total corporate tax revenue\\}\\} of almost \u20ac12 billion.", "Answer": "part, Finance, total corporate tax revenue"}, {"Question": "The ministers look certain to signal support for a deal and reports on Thursday evening pointed to efforts to achieve a breakthrough on key details, including \\{\\{0:a global minimum \\{\\{1:corporate tax\\}\\} rate\\}\\} of 15 per cent, above the Republic\u2019s 12.5 per \\{\\{2:cent rate\\}\\}.", "Answer": "a global minimum corporate tax rate, corporate tax, cent rate"}, {"Question": "Photograph: Hollie Adams/EPA\nFinance ministers from the main industrialised countries are set to discuss a deal on the reform of \\{\\{0:the global \\{\\{1:corporate tax\\}\\} system\\}\\} , including a minimum tax rate for \\{\\{2:multinationals\\}\\}, at a G7 meeting in London this weekend.", "Answer": "the global corporate tax system, corporate tax, multinationals"}, {"Question": "Donohoe to meet with \\{\\{0:US treasury secretary\\}\\} at \\{\\{1:bilateral meeting\\}\\} on \\{\\{2:Saturday\\}\\}\n", "Answer": "US treasury secretary, bilateral meeting, Saturday"}, {"Question": "The ante has been upped ahead of the meeting by a decision by the \\{\\{0:US\\}\\} to apply tariffs on $2 billion of imports from Austria, India, Italy, Spain, Turkey and the UK in retaliation for these countries implementing their own digital services taxes on \\{\\{2:US multinationals\\}\\}.", "Answer": "US, tax, US multinationals"}]}, {"Title": "Stephen Collins: What price Irish neutrality in today's world?", "URL": "https://www.irishtimes.com/opinion/stephen-collins-what-price-irish-neutrality-in-today-s-world-1.4583398", "Cards": [{"Question": "Nowadays \\{\\{0:UN peacekeeping operations\\}\\} are often subcontracted out to \\{\\{1:Nato\\}\\} or the \\{\\{2:EU\\}\\}.", "Answer": "UN peacekeeping operations, Nato, EU"}, {"Question": "In 1999 Ireland joined the \\{\\{0:Nato\\}\\} partnership for peace and more recently we have engaged with moves towards \\{\\{2:closer European defence arrangements\\}\\}.", "Answer": "Nato, part, closer European defence arrangements"}, {"Question": "\\{\\{0:Close defence co\\}\\}-\\{\\{1:operation\\}\\} with our fellow \\{\\{2:EU\\}\\} member states is an important statement of the nation\u2019s values and is also vital for its future security\n", "Answer": "Close defence co, operation, EU"}, {"Question": "The answer to both is that close \\{\\{0:defence co\\}\\}-\\{\\{1:operation\\}\\} with our fellow \\{\\{2:EU\\}\\} member states is an important statement of the nation\u2019s values and is also vital for its future security.", "Answer": "defence co, operation, EU"}, {"Question": "The Department of Foreign Affairs in its submission to the Commission on \\{\\{0:Defence\\}\\} has stressed that closer co-\\{\\{1:operation\\}\\} with the European Defence Agency and \\{\\{2:Nato\\}\\} is increasingly important.", "Answer": "Defence, operation, Nato"}, {"Question": "The need for a full public discussion about these issues is long overdue so that the debate is not hijacked by small vocal groups who oppose any form of \\{\\{0:defence co\\}\\}-\\{\\{2:operation\\}\\} with our neighbours.", "Answer": "defence co, -, operation"}, {"Question": "Polls show majority of \\{\\{0:voters\\}\\} in \\{\\{1:favour\\}\\} of \\{\\{2:closer EU defence and security arrangements\\}\\}\n", "Answer": "voters, favour, closer EU defence and security arrangements"}, {"Question": "A number of \\{\\{0:recent opinion polls\\}\\} have shown a clear majority of voters in \\{\\{1:favour\\}\\} of \\{\\{2:closer EU defence and security arrangements\\}\\}.", "Answer": "recent opinion polls, favour, closer EU defence and security arrangements"}]}]